Thomas I. Bereknyei

Mobile: 650-704-1166 Email:tomberek@gmail.com

Technical planner and developer with 10 years of experience planning operations and designing systems in both business and military settings working with researchers, engineers, operators, and end-users to create efficient and creative solutions.

- Experienced project manager as lead planner for technical and operational wargames involving multiple organizations at distributed locations.
- Proven ability to identify and implement decisive solutions with significant business and operational impact.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Exercise Director 2013 — Present Marine Forces Cyberspace Command Fort Meade, MD https://github.com/tomberek https://keybase.io/tomberek https://tomberek.info/resume

- Manage MARFORCYBER exercise participation, scheduling, and long-term development. Transformed ad hoc scheduling into a formal multi-year exercise support plan.
- Lead planner for CYBER FLAG 15 and CYBER GUARD 15 exercises; scenario design, Command and Control construct, network/target design, logistics for 118 participants, and development of training objectives. CYBER FLAG 15 is a USCYBERCOM led force-on-force cyberspace training exercise fusing attack and defense across a full spectrum of military operations. CYBER FLAG 15 was the first example of a headquarters element and supporting teams operating distributed across the nation. Provided technical information technology expertise regarding network vulnerabilities and cyberspace threats. These exercises include the design and exploitation of full enterprise Windows environments (up to regional and national networks) as well as attack platforms and replication of public Internet services.
- Developed a repeatable exercise support package for MAWTS-1 for Weapons Tactics Instructor Course (WTI); integrating the first Cyberspace Electronic Warfare Coordination Cell (CEWCC) into student events and provided technical guidance for scenario development and integration with kinetic operations. Repeated iterations of the exercise throughout 2014-2015 showcased a safe means of integrating cyberspace operations.
- Adopted an architectural framework to create a structured battlespace management methodology encompassing non-kinetics; Electronic Warfare, Cyberspace Operations, and the rest of Information Operations. The layered model allows for abstraction, separation of concerns, de-confliction, and common terminology used to sub-divide the information domain. This model was used during exercises to provide feedback for cyberspace doctrine development.

Senior Software Engineer 2014 — Present (part time) OpenTable Inc. San Francisco CA (remote)

OpenTable Inc.

San Francisco, CA (remote)

- Part-time contractor for Copilot Labs Inc. (getcopilot.com) until acquisition by OpenTable Inc. and renewed contract to perform DevOps and developer functions: maintain servers and back-end infrastructure, plan and execute major upgrades and migrations, design a continuous integration development and production environment, develop tools and utilities for administrators, and establish a security program.
- Transitioned standalone servers into a scalable and fault-tolerant cluster architecture utilizing Amazon Web Services including; EC2, S3, RDS, IAM, Elastic Beanstalk, EMR, ElastiCache, CloudWatch, and Route 53. Primary technologies used: Python, Django, MySQL, SQLite, Apache, nginx, Docker, Jenkins, git/Github, and a liberal abuse of shell scripting.
- Improved the workflow and testing capabilities for developers and designers. Automated scaling for future expansion and business growth.
- Performed security testing and a basic security audit of systems. Resolved critical

TECHNOLOGY

LINKS

Virtualization...... 6 years. Cloud Development..... 4 years. Functional Programming 6 years. Object Oriented Programming . . . Java Virtual Machine. . . . 6 years. DevOps..... 4 years. Linux Administration . . . 11 years. Electronic Warfare..... 6 years.

CLEARANCE AND CERTIFICATIONS

Current Top Secret Clearance

TS//SCI with Counterintelligence Polygraph

CISSP

2015



SharePoint Server

Microsoft SharePoint Server Site Owner/Power User

EDUCATION

University of California

Berkeley

B.S in Mechanical Engineering Minor: Electrical Engineering and Computer Science

Berkeley, CA

vulnerabilities such as Heartbleed and ShellShock within 24 hours of public disclosure.

Sought this position after years of participating in Open Source programming and maintaining development skills during military service. This provided an initial opportunity to work in a small startup setting until acquisition where now the goal is to integrate with a larger organization.

Software Contractor

Various clients

 Produced Scala and Haskell libraries and provided technical instruction as required by clients on an hourly basis.

• Regular expression demonstration. http://RegexPlanet.com/advanced/haskell/index.html

• SEG-Y geophysical binary data parser. https://github.com/Toeplitz/haskell

Critical learning point was the importance of formal project specification and clear communication with clients to develop requirements. Several projects grew in scope, consuming additional time and attention.

Electronic Warfare Officer

Marine Tactical Electronic Warfare Squadron 4

Cherry Point, NC Flew over 900 hours in the <u>EA-6B Prowler</u> as an Electronic Counter-Measures Officer with 70 combat sorties for 291.1 combat hours with multiple deployments to Operation Enduring Freedom.

- After basic trainig and Initially assigned to the Operations Department as a scheduler and quickly becoming the Subject Matter Expert for multiple ICAP III weapon systems and support systems. Familiarity with the systems and tactics led to an early assignment as the Electronic Warfare Department Head for Exercise Red Flag Alaska and deployment to MCAS Iwakuni, Japan. Simultaneously held collateral billets as Tactics Officer, Operational Security Officer, Classified Material Control Center Custodian, and Joint Mission Planning System Officer.
- Created a novel electronic attack technique applicable to several target sets and relying on an optimizing algorithm. Confirmed the tactic in coordination with Johns Hopkins University Jammer Technique Optimization Team and employed it in combat operations. Documented and corrected long-standing deficiencies in the tactical employment of the EA-6B by optimizing for the delivery of jamming power to a target. The opportunities to solve technical and tactical challenges in an operational squadron and in collaboration with experts were rewarding professional experiences.

Technical Solutions Specialist

Google Inc.

Mountain View, CA

- Identified and prevented fraud in Google AdSense and AdWords by both automated tools and alert systems. Investigated flagged incidents for fraudulent
- Leveraged existing machine learning algorithms such as self-organizing maps and classifying neural networks to discover novel click-fraud patterns of behavior. Revealed and terminated several multi-million dollar accounts engaged in click duplication and traffic replication.
- This position required a change of perspectives and thinking like a malicious actor; designing automated processes that can be utilized at a large scale.

SKILLS

IT Project Management

- Planned two critical infrastructure migrations while minimizing business impact
- Operated budget and planned the participation of up to 118 personnel in multiple locations for large exercises.
- Developed logistics to maintain technical support to tactical operations during movements of personnel and equipment.

Leadership 2006 Officer Candidate School Basic Officer Course Quantico, VA Naval Aviation Flight Training Designated as a Naval Flight eLance.com Officer Pensacola, FL

Electronic Countermeasures Officer Training EA-6B NATOPS qualified Whidbey Island, WA S.E.R.E. Training 2005 — 2013 Survival, Escape, Resistance, and Evasion

> **Expeditionary Warfare** School Military planning methodology and doctrine

Misc

- Fluent Hungarian
- Brew homemade fruit wine
- Homemade sourdough bread
- Martial arts: Judo/Jiu-Jitsu

 Experienced with Microsoft Project, SharePoint, and version control software (git, SVN, Darcs) for project management.

Programming

- Maintained a Haskell graph algorithm library and web-framework extension enabling FastCGI. Contributed to web-framework security.
 https://www.fpcomplete.com/user/tomberek/adding-security-to-mflow.
 <a href="https://www.fpcomplete.com/user/tomberek/adding-security-to-mflow-tomberek/adding-security-to-mflow-tomberek/adding-security-to-mflow-tomberek/adding-security-to-mflow-tomberek/adding-security-to-mflow-tomberek/adding-security-to-mflow-tomberek/adding-security-to-mflow-tomberek/adding-security-to-mflow-to-mflow-to-mflow-to-mflow-tomberek/adding-security-to-mflow-to-mflow-to-mfl
- Creating a Haskell library for opportunistic normalization for dataflows and computations.
- Developed popular Python plugin in 2010, "Learn Mode", for Anki http://ankisrs.net which was integrated into subsequent versions.
- Created customized database and frontend for a department of the U.S. Embassy in Hungary.
- Currently bootstrapping a Forth variant from assembly to the <u>Mill CPU</u>, a statically scheduled, wide issue, in-order architecture which uses a belt of temporary values rather than registers as a computing model.

System Administration and DevOps

- Used Linux commercially, on desktop, and personal servers since 2001. Tried RedHat, Ubuntu, Arch, (and Plan 9!) before becoming involved with NixOS due to its purely functional philosophy regarding configuration, upgrades, deterministic builds, and a mix of binary and source distribution. Currently maintain 15 packages with 100% build status.
- Supported experimental, development, continuous integration, and production environments for Copilot Labs Inc. and subsequently for OpenTable Inc.
- Experienced with virtualization, including VMWare, vSphere, XEN, QEMU, as well as Amazon Web Services (AWS) and many public and private cloud platforms.
- Maintain a honeypot in order to investigate current trends in remote exploitation.